Guide to the Archie Brown Papers ALBA.207
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Archie Brown Papers
1935-2002, (Bulk 1936-1946-1960-1997)
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Brown, Archie, 1911-1990.
ALBA.207
4.5 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
Archie Brown (1911-1990) -- San Francisco waterfront unionist, Communist Party organizer, and active member of the Bay Area Post of the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade -- fought with the Abraham Lincoln Brigade in Spain and participated in the Battle of the Bulge during WWII. He served on the Executive Board of International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union, Local 10, was prosecuted under the Landrum-Griffin Act barring Communists from serving as elected union officials, and won a Supreme Court decision in 1965 that overturned this legislation. This collection documents the full range of his career. Included is his correspondence from Spain and WWII, materials related to his union activism, legal documents pertaining to his indictment and appeal, and personal family papers. These records also provide a comprehensive account of West Coast VALB activities from the 1970s through the 1990s.
Provenance
The Archie Brown Collection was donated to New York University by Brown's widow, Esther Matlin Brown, in March 2003.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.
Historical/Biographical Note
Archie Brown was born on March 5, 1911 in Sioux City, Iowa to Nathan and Sarah Brown, Russian Jews who immigrated to the United States in the early years of the 20th century. In America, the family name of Breen was changed to Brown, and Nathan, a peddler by trade in Russia, struggled to support his wife and eight children as a teamster in Sioux City, delivering bread and meat to Jewish households throughout the region. In search of greater economic opportunity, Nathan relocated to Oakland, California, and soon after, 13-year-old Archie hopped a freight train to join his father and older brother in gainful employment. There he hawked newspapers and was initiated into labor activism while participating in a newsboys' strike in 1928. Members of the Trade Union Education League (TUEL), the labor-organizing wing of the Communist Party, helped the newsboys advance their cause, and fostered Brown's political education. He joined the Young Communist League (YCL) the following year and soon was taking part in efforts to organize agricultural workers, many of them migrant Mexicans and Dust-Bowl refugees. Brown's talents as a persuasive and indefatigable organizer came to the fore early on. A frequent orator at rallies and meetings, Brown was arrested at a YCL event in San Pedro in 1934 and charged with disturbing the peace; he received a three-month sentence. Following his release, he joined the International Longshoremen's Association, a forerunner to the International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union (ILWU), and became a moving force in organizing waterfront workers in the San Francisco Bay area. It was during this time that Brown met Esther ("Hon") Matlin at a YCL dance. By 1936 the couple were married. Theirs was an enduring union that produced four children and lasted over 50 years.
With the overthrow of the popularly elected government in Spain by fascist forces in 1936, the Communist Party began recruiting volunteers to join the International Brigades' defense of the beleaguered nation. Brown's younger brother Frank ("Bimbo") was among the initial recruits from ILWU, Local 10 to enter the fray early in 1937. Archie, by now an important Party leader and well-known labor radical in the San Francisco area, was denied a passport by the local passport agency (his claims of wanting to pursue studies in France were met with incredulity). Undeterred, he traveled to New York City and in May 1938, after three months of unsuccessful efforts to obtain a passport, stowed away on a ship bound for France, to make his way to Spain. He arrived in time to serve with the Lincoln Brigade as company commissar in the Ebro Offensive and in the final bloody retreats of the war. Following the withdrawal of the International Brigades from Spain, Brown sailed from France to New York (this time as a third-class passenger) on the S.S. Ausonia in December 1938.
Back in San Francisco, Brown returned to the waterfront and the Communist Party. In 1940, Brown ran for the Congress in the 4th District on the CP ticket. Although never elected, he was for many years a perennial candidate for a variety of offices on the Party line. During World War II, Brown enlisted in the U.S. Army, trained at Fort Hood, Texas and, in February 1945, shipped out to Europe where he participated in the Battle of the Bulge with the 76th Infantry Division. He remained overseas until early 1946, serving with the occupation forces in Europe. Upon his return he was named state trade-union director for the Communist Party. Cold War politics made the labor movement and the militant left targets of mounting hostility and judicial assault. Brown was directed by the CP to go into hiding, and for four years he led a shadow existence shuttling between safe houses and permitted only rare visits with his family. He emerged again in 1955, resumed work as a longshoreman and, although he resigned from his full-time position as a Communist Party organizer, remained a staunch adherent to the movement.
During the final years of the 1950s, Brown continued his union activities and served as an Executive Board member of the ILWU, Local 10. In 1960 Brown was subpoenaed and appeared as a hostile witness before the House Un-American Activities Committee at hearings held in San Francisco's City Hall. As Brown delivered a defiant statement, protestors against the proceedings poured into the hearing room. Pandemonium erupted and the Committee had Brown forcibly ejected. Three days of demonstrations ensued, led to scores of arrests, and earned Brown national notoriety for his role in the protests. By the following year, Brown was again drawing fire. This time he was arrested and charged with violation of a provision of the 1959 Landrum-Griffin Act which barred Communists from serving as union officers. In 1963 he was convicted. Following a Federal Court of Appeals decision in Brown's favor, the U.S. Supreme Court struck down the legislation in 1965. Brown retired from Local 10 in 1977 and, with Hon, assumed the leadership of the Bay Area Post of the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB). Along with members of VALB, Brown engaged in a range of activist efforts, including protests on behalf of the Sandinistas in Nicaragua and in opposition to the Pinochet government in Chile, and the provision of humanitarian aid and technical support to El Salvador and Cuba. In 1986 Brown, and veterans from around the world, returned to Spain to mark the 50th anniversary of the formation of the International Brigades. On November 23, 1990, Brown died after battling cancer. He was 79 years old.
Sources:
Schwartz, Stephen. "Archie Brown: He Won Key Court Ruling." San Francisco Chronicle, November 22, 1990.
Wiese, Timothy. "San Francisco Labor Activist Archie Brown." MA thesis, Sonoma State University, 1999.
Scope and Content Note
Series I: Personal Papers, 1936-1990. The materials in this series document the broad range of Brown's experiences from the months leading up to and including his time in Spain, through his WWII service, and into the 1960s and the court cases related to his union's violation of the Landrum-Griffin Act. This series also includes family papers and memorabilia.
Sub-series A: Spanish Civil War. This subseries contains Brown's letters to his wife Esther -- referred to as "Hon" -- that cover the period from his departure from California in February 1938, through his return to New York in December 1938. In these letters he recounts his cross-country journey to New York City and sojourn there, the outgoing voyage as a stowaway his duties in Spain, and his political observations. Esther was also the recipient of letters from other volunteers including Douglas Male and Archie's brother Frank (Bimbo), and these letters can also be found in this series. Additional materials include military documents, identification and membership cards; a copy of Volunteer for Liberty annotated with Spanish and American signatures; and a seven-page handwritten letter to Brown from Harry Bridges, President of the International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union (ILWU), with news of the waterfront unions and the State A.F.L. convention.
Subseries B: World War II. In addition to Brown's letters to Hon documenting his military service from June 1944 through January 1946, there are several V-mail letters from fellow Abraham Lincoln Brigade veteran John (Jack) Lucid, military documents, and Brown's dog tags. Also in this series are several letters written by Brown to his young son Douglas, offering gentle instruction on class struggle, race and the evils of bigotry.
Subseries C: General. Among the materials to be found in this series are legal briefs and clippings related to Brown's indictment and appeal for violation of the Landrum-Griffin Act; documents related to his activities with the waterfront workers and the International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union (ILWU); Brown's Communist Party membership card and a piece of his election campaign literature; correspondence from supporters and detractors; and materials related to his wife Hon, their children and their extended family. Also here is a copy of Timothy Wiese's master's thesis on Archie Brown's long career as a radical labor activist.
Series II: Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Bay Area Post, 1940; 1967-2002.This series, consisting of records of the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Bay Area Post, offers a comprehensive account of the West Coast veterans' activities from the 1970s through the 1990s. Included in these records are minutes, correspondence, and materials related to annual celebrations and events; documentation of VALB's activism on behalf of El Salvador and Nicaragua; and clippings and memorabilia related to anniversary visits by Abraham Lincoln and International Brigades veterans to Spain. These records also reflect Esther Brown's ongoing work on behalf of VALB following her husband's death in 1990.
Series III: Oversize Material, 1945; 1960.This series includes two folders: a folder of clippings pertaining to the House Committee on Un-American Activities hearings and protest, and a folder of Armed Forces periodicals from WWII.
Arrangement
Series I is arranged alphabetically within each sub-series. Series II and III are arranged alphabetically.
The files are grouped into three series:
Missing Title
I, Personal Papers, 1936-1990
A: Spanish Civil War
B: World War II
C: General
II, Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Bay Area Post, 1940; 1967-2002
III, Oversize Material, 1945; 1960
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
John (Jack) M. Lucid Papers, ALBA #206.
Douglas Wayne Male Papers, ALBA #223.
ALBA collections at the Tamiment Library.
Separated Material
Photographs and audiotapes from the Archie Brown Collection have been transferred to the non-print section of the ALBA collection in the Tamiment Library.
Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Campaigns.; Briefs (legal documents); Personal papers.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.; Labor unions |x Law and legislation |z United States.; Ebro River, Battle of the, Spain, 1938.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, American.; United States |x Armed Forces |v Periodicals.; Barcelona (Spain); Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |v Periodicals.; Correspondence.; Articles.; Legal documents.; Bridges, Harry, 1901-; Brown, Archie, 1911-1990.; Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Abraham Lincoln Battalion; United States. Army; Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade; Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Brigada Internacional, XV; Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion; Communist Party of the United States of America; Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives; Wiese, Timothy; International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union; Male, Douglas Wayne.; Lucid, John M., 1915-1977; Brown, Frank; Brown, Esther Matlin
- Series I: Personal Papers
  - Subseries A: Spanish Civil War
    - Associacio d'Amics de la Unio-Sovietica: Membership Card, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Billeting Pass, Nov 1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Carnet Militar, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Christmas Greetings: Issued by International Brigades, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Citations and Certificates of Merit issued by: International Brigade; Ministerio de la Guerra (Spanish Army); Socors Roig de Catalunya; Union de Muchachas, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Bridges, Harry to Archie Brown, Sep 1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Brown, Archie to Esther (Hon) Brown, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Brown, Archie to Esther (Hon) Brown, Feb 1938-May 1938 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: Brown, Archie to Esther (Hon) Brown, Jun 1938-Jul 1938 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: Brown, Archie to Esther (Hon) Brown, Aug 1938-Sep 1938 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: Brown, Archie to Esther (Hon) Brown, Oct 1938-Dec 1938 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: Brown, Esther (Hon) to Archie Brown, Sep 1938 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: Brown, Frank (Bimbo) to Archie Brown, Nov 1937-May 1938 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: Brown Frank (Bimbo) to Esther (Hon) Brown, Apr 1938 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: Eggen, Julius Jack Leonard to Esther Brown, Sep 1936 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: International Association of Machinists to Archie Brown, Oct 1938 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence: Male, Douglas to "Mother", undated, Nov 1938 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence: Smith, Oliver to Archie Brown, Jan 1939 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence: Villar, Jose to Archie Brown, Dec 1938 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - English - Spanish Grammar (Prepared for the English-speaking units of the International Brigades), 1938 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Orders of the Day (photocopies), Feb 1937-Nov 1937 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Our Fight (15th Brigade Newsletter), Aug 1938 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Postcard: Fleet of the Spanish Republic (inscribed by "Jim"), undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Sailing Ephemera: Berthing and Dining Cards, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Socors Roig de Catalunya: Membership Card, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Spanish Communist Party: Membership Card, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Voice of the Federation (Maritime Federation of the Pacific): "Archie Brown Sends More Word from Spain," clipping, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Volunteer for Liberty (Annotated with Spanish and American signatures), Sep 1938 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Subseries B: World War II
    - Brown, Esther: Military Pass, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence: Brown, Archie to Douglas Brown, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence: Brown, Archie to Esther (Hon) Brown, Jun 1944-Aug 1944 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence: Brown, Archie to Esther (Hon) Brown, Sep 1944-Oct 1944 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence: Brown, Archie to Esther (Hon) Brown, Nov 1944-Dec 1944 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence: Brown, Archie to Esther Brown, Jan 1945-Feb 1945 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence: Brown, Archie to Esther (Hon) Brown, Mar 1945-Apr 1945 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence: Brown, Archie to Esther (Hon) Brown, May 1945-Jun 1945 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence: Brown, Archie to Esther (Hon) Brown, Jul 1945-Aug 1945 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence: Brown, Archie to Esther (Hon) Brown, Sep 1945-Oct 1945 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence: Brown, Archie to Esther (Hon) Brown, Nov 1945-Jan 1946 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence: Brown, Esther (Hon) to Archie Brown, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence: Dobbs, Benjamin to Archie Brown, Nov 1945 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence: Lucid, John (Jack) to Archie Brown (V-Mail), Aug 1943-Dec 1943 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence: Odette to Archie Brown (in French and English), Oct 1945 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Documents and Ephemera: Safe Conduct Pass, Ration Card, Receipts, Nazi Propaganda, Letter (German and French), 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Dog Tags, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Graphic Work: Satirical Cartoon of Army Life (in pencil), undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Military Documents: Pay Record, Ration Card, Personnel Record, Immunization Register, Certificate of Captured Equipment, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Selective Service Classification Cards, 1940-1944 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - World War II: Armed Forces Periodicals [See Series III: Oversize Material], 1945
  - Subseries C: General
    - Anti-Semitism: Articles, 1965-1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Black, Elaine: Clippings and Leaflet (photocopies), 1935 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Brown, Archie: Communist Party Membership Book, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Brown, Archie: Identity and Membership Cards, undated, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Brown, Archie: Retirement Testimonial, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Brown, Archie: "San Francisco Labor Activist Archie Brown" (Master's Thesis by Timothy Wiese), 1999 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Brown, Archie: Union and Membership Cards; Dues Book; Pay Stubbs, undated, 1936-1944 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Brown, Archie: Young Communist League: Membership Card and Delegate Ticket, 1935, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Brown, Esther: Membership and Picket Cards, Certificates, HS Diploma, Clipping, undated, 1935-1945, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Brown Family: Birth and Anniversary Announcements; Report Card, 1937-1955, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Citizens Exchange Corp: Soviet Amity Trip, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Communist Party Campaign Literature (San Francisco): Archie Brown for Congress, 4th District, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Communist Party: Clippings, undated, 1961-1981 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: Brown, Archie to Esther (Birthday Cards and Notes), undated, 1940-1990 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: Brown Children (Susan, Douglas, Stephanie), undated, 1949-1952, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: Crank Letters, undated, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence: General, undated, 1942-1987 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence: Hall, Gus, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence: Matlin Family to Esther Brown, undated, 1935-1938 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA): FBI File and Correspondence, 1962-1978 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - House Committee on Un-American Activities: San Francisco Hearings and Protest, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - House Committee on Un-American Activities: San Francisco Hearings and Protest: Clippings [See Series III: Oversize Material], 1960
    - International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union (ILWU), undated, 1938-1974 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Landrum-Griffin Act: Archie Brown Indictment and Appeal, 1961-1965 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Landrum-Griffin Act: Archie Brown Indictment and Appeal: Clippings, 1961-1965 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Mementos and Artifacts: Package of Germany Cigarettes, Two Small Flags with Five-pointed Star, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Partido dels Comuniste de Catalunya: Pamphlet and Stickers, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Repatriation of Greek Political Refugees: International Conference, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - San Francisco County Campaign Committee, Communist Party: Archie Brown for Congress, 4th District: Leaflet, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Schneiderman-Darcy Defense Committee, [1952] (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Travel: Germany, France, Belgium, Soviet Union, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Travel: Spain, Greece, Naples, Kiev (Notes and Correspondence), 1979 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Wofsy, Leon: "What's Happening to Soviet Socialism", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Workmen's Time Book, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Series II: VALB: Bay Area Post
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives, 1989-2000 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Anniversary: 4th Commemoration, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Anniversary: 30th - 34th Commemorations, 1967-1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Anniversary: 39th Commemoration, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Anniversary: 41st Commemoration, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Anniversary: 42nd - 44th Commemorations, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Anniversary: 45th Commemoration, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Anniversary: 46th Commemoration, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Anniversary: 47th Commemoration, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Anniversary: 48th Commemoration, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Anniversary: 50th Commemoration: Dinner, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Anniversary: 50th Commemoration: Exhibits, Events, Performances, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Anniversary: 51st Commemoration, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Anniversary: 52nd Commemoration, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Anniversary: 53rd Commemoration, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Anniversary: 54th Commemoration, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Anniversary: 55th Anniversary, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Anniversary: 56th Commemoration, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Anniversary: 57th Commemoration, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Anniversary: 58th Commemoration, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Anniversary: 59th Commemoration, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Anniversary: 62nd Commemoration, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Anniversary: 63rd Commemoration, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Australian Volunteers, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Chile: Politics and Aid, undated, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Chile: Valparaiso Maritime Workers, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Communist Party of Canada, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, undated, 1963-1974 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1975-1985 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence, 1998-2002 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cuba: Politics and Aid, 1991-1997 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - El Salvador: Caravan for Peace and Reconstruction, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - El Salvador: Medical Aid, undated, 1985-1992 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - El Salvador: Politics, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Fasanella, Ralph, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Financial Reports, 1986-2001 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Fundacion Dolores Ibarruri, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Homenaje a las Brigadas Internacionales, Oct 1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - International Brigades, 1984-1981 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Jewish Participation in the Spanish Civil War, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Jewish Participation in the Spanish Civil War: Monument, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Polish Veterans (Dombrowski Brigade): Pension Benefits, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - McCarran Act: VALB Defense, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion, 1978, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - MacKenzie- Papineau Battalion: Monument, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Minutes: Bay Area VALB Post, undated, 1985-2002 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Minutes: New York VALB Post, undated, 1989-1992 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Monument: Barcelona, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Monument: Seattle, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Monument: VALB Bay Area Members, 1997-2002 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Monuments: Clippings, 1994-1998 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - National Conference, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 23)